Guide to the Michael F. Marmor Papers Pertaining to Research on Woodrow Wilson
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Michael F. Marmor papers pertaining to research on Woodrow Wilson
1896-1998
1967-1998
SC0873
Marmor, Michael F., 1941-
2 Linear feet
Papers pertain to research done by Marmor along with Alexander L. George and Juliette L. George on Wilson?s health, in particular his ocular health, and include correspondence, articles, and historic sources.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Marmor, who received his A.B. and M.D. at Harvard, is Professor of ophthalmology at Stanford School of Medicine and active in undergraduate education in the Program in Human Biology. In addition to his medical research, he has studied the relationship of vision and eye disease to art.
Description of the Collection
Papers pertain to research done by Marmor along with Alexander L. George and Juliette L. George on Wilson?s health, in particular his ocular health, and include correspondence, articles, and historic sources.
Access Terms
George, Alexander L.; George, Juliette L.; Marmor, Michael F., 1941-; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.; Presidents--United States--Health.; Vision disorders.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Wilson research, Alexander L. and Juliette L. George, articles and correspondence, 1983-98 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Historical Journal, correspondence and text of article by Marmor and the George’s, 1982-83 (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Historical Journal (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Weinstein, Edwin – Reviews and correspondence re his book on Wilson, 1982-85 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - “Bad Case of History” – text and correspondence re Marmor’s review of Weinstein’s book, 1982-83 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - D.C. Meeting and Jerrold M. Post, correspondence and articles, 1982-83 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - TV film on Wilson by Ron T. Carter, correspondence, 1984-85 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - “Wilson, Strokes, and Zebras” – Press, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - “Wilson, Strokes, and Zebras” – correspondence, 1981-88 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Illustration Materials (includes photographs, negatives, and correspondence) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - JAMA 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - “Eyes of Woodrow Wilson” – reprint, correspondence, and misc. data, 1984-85 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Medical opinions re ocular stroke, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - General eye – articles and notes (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Other Commentators (MDs), articles and correspondence 1982-86 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Other Commentators (MDs), articles and correspondence 1982-86 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence re Wilson research (of both Marmor and Alexander and Juliette George) 1981-86 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Prescriptions (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Political Science Quarterly, article by Alexander and Juliette George 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Stroke References in Papers of Woodrow Wilson (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Papers of Woodrow Wilson – Extracts (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Examples of WW’s Handwriting (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Baker, R. S., Woodrow Wilson’s Life and Letters – extracts from (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Stockton Axson, copies of his manuscript on WW (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Weinstein summaries – correspondence and articles, 1967-83 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Wilson’s stroke of 1896 – sources, data, etc. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Wilson’s stroke of 1906 – sources, data, etc. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Wilson’s stroke of 1919 – data summaries (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Wilson’s stroke of 1919 – articles, correspondence (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - George, A. L. and George, J. L., “Woodrow Wilson and Colonel House,” typescript paper 1981 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - General articles and correspondence 1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Diary of Dr. Cary T. Grayson, 12/3/1918-5/7/1919 (photocopy from the papers of Woodrow Wilson at Princeton University) (Box 5, Folder 1)